Richa Kaur

Business Analyst

Business-minded analyst with a demonstrated ability to deliver valuable insight via data analytics and advanced data driven methods. Particularly relied on mathematical and technological background to attain a meaningful solution. Good technical experience in implementing machine learning algorithms.

Rourkela, Odisha

© (+91)9090302071

https://richakbee.github.io/





EDUCATION

- BTech in Computer Science & Engineering (with Honors), 9.1 CGPA BPUT, Odisha- 2019
- St. Josephs Convent School, Rourkela (1995-2013), 90 % in X, 89% in XII

SKILLS

- Tools & Framework Python3, Jupyter, Tensor flow, keras, Sklearn, AutoML, pandas, Pycaret, Tableau, MS office, Flutter, Android Studio, Aws/Azure/GCP, SQL, MongoDB.
- Techniques Regression,
 Classification , Clustering , Bagging,
 Boosting, Dimensionality Reduction ,
 Hyper Parameter Tuning ,Data
 Visualization ,Exploratory Data Analysis,
 Data Mining , Feature engineering, Data
 Wrangling ,Web Scraping ,ANN , CNN ,
 RNN (basic),NLP (basic) , Transfer Learning
 , Deployment, Advanced Data Analytics.

COURSES & CERTIFICATION

- <u>Deep Learning Specialization</u>,
 Coursera.
- <u>DeepLearning.Al TensorFlow</u>
 <u>Developer</u>, Coursera.
- Applied Data Science in Python
 Specialization ,University of Michigan
- <u>Descriptive Statistics with R</u>,
 IIT Kanpur , NPTEL
- Data Mining , IIT Kharagpur ,NPTEL
- Intro to Statistics , Udacity
- Intro to Descriptive Statistics, Udacity
- Intro to Inferential Statistics ,Udacity
- Hands On Tableau A-Z, Udemy
- Machine Learning , Stanford University.

AWARDS

 Scholarship awardee for being top of the batch in 2nd, 3rd, 4th, 5th semester

STRENGTHS

- Oral & Written Communication
- Committed to Lifelong Learning
- Team Building

Hobbies

- Fitness : Yoga ,Strength Training @gym
- Adventure : Hiking , Trekking , Camping
- Book Reading (atleast 10 pages / day)
- Sports:. Carrom, Chess, Badminton (award winning)

WORK EXPERIENCE

NMTechnosol (with @Affine Analytics)
Business Analyst

July-2019 - Present

Roles & Responsibilities:-

- Understanding Business Problem and domain by interacting with onsite.
- Remotely working for world's second largest animal health company
- Implemented Initial EDA deck and Visualization Dashboard to understand data behavior.
- Advanced analytics, Derive insights from transaction level data.
- Served various on-site adhoc analytical requests.
- Dashboard creation, monthly maintenance and story telling with Tableau
- Identified KPI for waterfall analysis for bulk purchasing potential of customers.
- Segregated Customers into Loyal ,Switch & new category & Performed Repeat purchase analysis to identify potential customers to improve sales.
- Defined Initial set of KPI's and Identified four clusters for Market segmentation using unsupervised machine learning techniques for targeted marketing.

Mindfire Solutions
Full Stack Web Developer (Intern)

January-2019 –June 2019

Roles & Responsibilities :-

- Created an end to end Blogging Site from scratch.
- Tools & Technologies include:
 - Front end: HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, AJAX, JQUERY
 - Back end : Cold Fusion.
 - Database : Microsoft SQL Server

PERSONAL LEARNING

- Sentiment Analysis
 — Worked on a Classification problem to understand sentiment hidden in text & classify if it is positive or negative. (on IMDB movie reviews)
- <u>Back Order Prediction</u> End to End ML application to detect if a product could come short & Order has to be cancelled.(inventory management)
- Big Mart Sales End to End ML application deployed on GCP to predict the sales
 of an item at a particular Outlet.
- Insurance Fraud Detection End to End ML application deployed on Azure to detect if the insurance claim is fraudulent or genuine.
- Image Classification Web app A Flask Object Segmentation app that classifies between cats & dogs images when uploaded by a user. (CNN)
- <u>Digit Recognizer (A deep learning app on flutter)</u> A its a Deep Learning app that recognizes Digits . Users have Two options : either upload an image of a digit or draw the digit on drawing space. CNN Model was created in TensorFlow. ..
- Demand Forecasting (Bike Sharing & Rental) A Regression problem to forecast the numbers of bikes to be rented at any hour of a day .(Kaggle challenge)